Patrick Dusseau

4210 Jackman ~ Ida, Michigan 48140 ~ (734) 770-9177

patrickdusseau9177@gmail.com

Background

Desktop Engineer with 10 years of experience in PC Hardware and Software installation and upgrades. System Center Configuration Manager utilization. Experienced in testing both hardware and software solutions, problem solving and troubleshooting. Experienced with Cisco switch/router configuration and installation. Assistant Telecom Engineer with experience in digital and VOIP phone installations. Well rounded auto/truck technician with over 30 years of experience. Proficient in Microsoft office products.

Objective

I would like to obtain a challenging position in the Automotive and IT field where my drive and ambition will be rewarded with the opportunity for growth and advancement.

Professional Experience

<u>January 2012-Present Mercy Memorial Hospital/Promedica Monroe Regional Hospital – Monroe, MI</u>

Desktop Engineer/Assistant Telecom Engineer/IT analyst

- Create advertisements for SCCM package pushes.
- o Install, troubleshoot and maintain software applications and hardware.
- Provide desktop and phone support to main hospital and remote locations.
- Use Microsoft Configuration Manager to push software updates to users.
- o Call assignment and tracking using Remedy Action Request System and Service Now.
- Active directory and DNS troubleshooting.
- Assist end users with questions or problems.
- o Assist Telecom Engineer with phone installations, programming, and troubleshooting.
- o Configure Cisco switch ports for work station installations.
- o Patch data cables in from work stations to Data closets.
- o Upgrade hardware and roll out EMR (All Scripts) to over 800 PC's
- o Receive, image, and deploy all new desktop hardware.
- Perform Data migration on all refreshed PC's
- o Perform Mechanical repairs on mobile PC carts.
- o Perform PC and laptop hardware repairs.

2010-2012

- Volunteer as a Desktop engineer Mercy Memorial Hospital IT department.
- Assist with hospital wide windows 7 upgrade.
- o Perform ram upgrade on 800 PC's and laptops

2007-2013

Owens Community College, Monroe County Community College

- Vocational retraining during recovery from serious accident.
- Maintained a 3.75 GPA throughout college.
- Deans list

August 2002-2005 Delker's Automotive-Temperance, MI

Lead Automotive/Heavy Truck Technician

- O Diagnose and repair mechanical, electrical, and on board computer failures.
- Document all repairs made using ALLDATA software.
- o Utilize ALLDATA data base to retrieve repair specs and recommended repair procedures.

March 2000-2002 R&R Fire Truck Repair- Northville, MI

Emergency Equipment Technician

- Maintain a mobile repair service truck and schedule all repair visits in a timely matter.
- o Diagnose and repair Firefighting and medical transport equipment.
- Repair onboard computers and electrical systems.
- Fire-pump overhauls and replacement.
- Responsible for scheduling and performing a wide range of repairs.
- o Service over 100 fire departments in lower Michigan.

March 1991-January 2000 Juckette's Service- Dundee, MI

Lead Automotive Technician

- Diagnose and repair mechanical, electrical, and on board computer failures.
- o Provide estimates to customers for repair costs.
- Use ALLDATA software to assist with repairs and estimates.
- o Manage shop operations several times a year while owner was away.

August 1985-1991 Harry May/Dunlap Chevrolet- Monroe, MI

Automotive Technician

- o Diagnose and repair mechanical, electrical, and on board computer failures.
- Automatic transmission overhauls.
- Heavy Engine repairs.
- Drivability Technician.

0

Education

Fall 2007-2009 Owens Community College (Deans List)

- Cisco Wide Area Networking.
- Designing and Supporting Cisco Networks.
- o Cisco Routing and Switching in an Enterprise environment.
- Diagnosis and Support of Cisco Computer networks.

Fall 2009-2013 Monroe County Community College – Monroe, MI Associates of Science with emphasis in Information Technology

- o Microsoft Office 2010-2013 Professional
- Web building and design.
- o PC operation systems Windows7/Linux

Skills

- o Critical Thinking, Customer Service.
- o Utilized effective communication and team collaboration skills.
- Strong organizational and problem solving skills.
- Scheduling and time management.
- Effective interpersonal skills.

References

Available upon request